<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Entity on Awesome Arabic Speakers</title><link>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/categories/entity/</link><description>Recent content in Entity on Awesome Arabic Speakers</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/categories/entity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Awesome Arabic Speakers</title><link>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/awesome-arabic-speakers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/awesome-arabic-speakers/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/img/awesome-arabic-speakers.png" alt="Featured image of post Awesome Arabic Speakers" />&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Awesome Arabic Speakers&lt;/a> a project aims to create a curated and collaborative list of awesome Arabic speaker&amp;rsquo;s contributions in tech regardless of their ethnicity, nationality, or location. Also, the contributions don&amp;rsquo;t have to be in Arabic to be useful and add value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arabic" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Arabic&lt;/a> is the third most widespread official language after English and French! It has &lt;strong>380 million&lt;/strong> native speakers of all varieties (2024).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We welcome contributions from everyone. The list covers many &lt;a class="link" href="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/categories/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>categories&lt;/a> like &lt;a class="link" href="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/categories/entity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Entity&lt;/a>, &lt;a class="link" href="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/categories/software/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Software&lt;/a>, &lt;a class="link" href="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/categories/multimedia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Multimedia&lt;/a>, &lt;a class="link" href="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/categories/text/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Text&lt;/a>, and &lt;a class="link" href="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/categories/event/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Event&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Libre Arabic Books</title><link>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/librebooks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/librebooks/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/librebooks/librebooks.png" alt="Featured image of post Libre Arabic Books" />&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://librebooks.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Libre Books&lt;/a> is a project that aims to encourage and enhance the Arabic content and support initiatives like Access to Knowledge, Open Access, Creative Commons. Also, to contribute to creating Free (as in freedom) content, as well as supporting people to start to create Free and Open books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It aims also to collect and give a database of Arabic Free/Libre books licensed under open source licenses like Creative Commons and GNU FDL. And also providing technical and logistic support to create high-quality Arabic books, as well as recreate good content in a more professional format to enhance and increase its benefit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to being an index for open-source Arabic books, the project has contributed to publishing a number of Arabic books on various topics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Manara</title><link>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/manara/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/manara/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/manara/manara.svg" alt="Featured image of post Manara" />&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://manara.tech/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Manara&lt;/a> is a public benefit corporation (PBC), a type of for-profit corporation created to generate social and public good. Manara aims to create a platform that supports software engineers and data scientists from the Middle East and North Africa (MENA) to match the global job market.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2024, Manara changed their model to be &lt;strong>free for all&lt;/strong>, more open, and available for more people. It offers self-paced training, expert assessments, resume reviews, and interview preparation, all designed by seasoned engineers. The free service aims to elevate tech skills and provide career opportunities with top global companies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>S3Geeks</title><link>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/s3geeks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/s3geeks/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/s3geeks/s3geeks.jpg" alt="Featured image of post S3Geeks" />&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://s3geeks.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>S3Geeks&lt;/a> is a non-profit organization established in 2011 by a group of young Egyptians from Upper Egypt (south). It works on spreading technology and the internet, specifically in Upper Egypt and generally in Egypt and the Middle East. The organization aims to organize and mobilize the efforts of Egyptian youth to establish a new community for tech entrepreneurs to advance and develop Upper Egypt as an integral part of Egypt. Over the years, their efforts have achieved great success, attracting the support and sponsorship of global companies. Their activities have expanded to cover all the governorates and cities of Upper Egypt. Sa3eedy Geeks is now considered the first platform for entrepreneurs and tech enthusiasts in Upper Egypt.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Awesome Egyptian Open Source</title><link>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/awesome-egyptian-open-source/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/awesome-egyptian-open-source/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/awesome-egyptian-open-source/awesome-egyptian-open-source.png" alt="Featured image of post Awesome Egyptian Open Source" />&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/mfouad/awesome-egypt-opensource" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Awesome Egyptian Open Source&lt;/a> is a platform that encourages open-source initiatives from Egyptian companies and independent engineers. It focuses on helping young developers find approachable projects and access mentorship in their native language for their first open-source contributions. Additionally, the project provides an up-to-date list of open-source projects, addressing the need for current resources beyond outdated news sites and documents. For those hiring, this platform is a valuable resource for discovering top-tier developers and companies for your next project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Syrian Open Source</title><link>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/syrian-open-source/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/syrian-open-source/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/syrian-open-source/syrian-open-source.png" alt="Featured image of post Syrian Open Source" />&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/Syrian-Open-Source" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Syrian Open Source&lt;/a> is a GitHub initiative to unite Syrian developers from diverse backgrounds to collaborate on open-source projects across various languages and versions. It seeks to encourage Syrian developers to contribute more to open-source software, enhance its quality and engineering, and promote the open-source concept within the Syrian software community. Additionally, the platform aims to boost developer efficiency by facilitating work on distributed systems and teams.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yemen Open Source</title><link>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/yemen-open-source/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/yemen-open-source/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/yemen-open-source/yemen-open-source.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Yemen Open Source" />&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/YemenOpenSource" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Yemen Open Source&lt;/a> is a developer&amp;rsquo;s platform that aims to improve the collaboration between Yemeni developers, foster creative thinking, and give back to the community. The project hopes to create a thriving community for Yemeni developers through open-source projects and tech-related difficulties, such as supporting Arabic and RTL concerns, easing payment gateway integrations, etc. Also, it aims to Arabize tech knowledge as much as possible and highlight outstanding initiatives by Yemeni developers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GeeksBlaBla</title><link>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/geeksblabla/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/geeksblabla/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://awesome-arabic-speakers.dev/p/geeksblabla/geeksblabla.svg" alt="Featured image of post GeeksBlaBla" />&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://geeksblabla.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>GeeksBlabla&lt;/a> is a tech community that shares and debates the newest IT subjects in Darija, the Moroccan Arabic language. It includes episodes and podcasts on various tech-related topics, such as AI tools, software engineering, programming, and success stories of Moroccan IT workers. The site has extensive debates and a sizable library of episodes with various guest lecturers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The project also has multiple sub-projects like:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://awesome-morocco.dev" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Awesome Morocco&lt;/a>: List of awesome Moroccan things for/by Developers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://stateofdev.ma" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>State Of Dev In Morocco&lt;/a>: Ultimate insight hub about Tech in Morocco.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://blablaconf.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>BlaBlaConf&lt;/a>: Your one-stop shop for the latest and hottest technology trends in Darija.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>